<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<dataroot xmlns:od="urn:schemas-microsoft-com:officedata" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"  xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="Seal.xsd" generated="2019-05-23T09:32:28">
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Adimari, Alemanno</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Adimarius2</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a nimbed man, standing, facing half-right right, holding a palm in the right hand and a book in the left hand, (St Eusebius?); on each side, in an aedicule, a nimbed and winged figure (angel) kneeling on a pedestal, facing inwards, with hands raised, held together; in a niche below a mitred man (cardinal), facing left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S	igillm alamanni tituli sci eusebii psbricardinalis

[Sigillum Alamanni Tituli Sancti Eusebii Presbiteri Cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Eusebio</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1411</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;la croix fleuronnée brochant&apos; - Inventaire des sceaux de Champagne, A. Coulon, Volume V: Papes, Cardinaux , Archevêques , évêques 1427-1602</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Adimari, Alemanno</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Adimarius3</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, on the left, the Virgin sitting on a bench, facing half-right, hands raised, held together; on the right, Christ sitting on a bench, facing half-left, hands raised, placing a crown on the Virgin&apos;s head; in a niche below, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, hands raised, held together; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Heraldry>Chacon col. 1086, A.1411.  McCarthy, v. 1, p. 157, &apos;Arms,- Per fess azure and or, a cross botonny gules.&apos;</Heraldry>
<Legend>Sigillm a[ . . . ]anni tituli sci eusebii ps[ . . . ] cardinalis

[Sigillum Alamanni Tituli Sancti Eusebii Presbiteri Cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Eusebio</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1411</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Aigrefeuille, Faydit</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>AigrefeuilleF1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length Virgin and Child; below, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man (St Sylvester or St Martin?), sitting on a bench, full face, his right hand raised in blessing, holding an indistinct object in his left hand; on each side in an aedicule a half-length nimbed and winged figure (angel), facing inwards, one hand raised to the chest; above; below in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S [ . . . ] MARTINI I[ . ] 	MON . . . ] 

[Sigillum . . . Sancti Martini in Montibus]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Martino ai Monti</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1383</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;trois étoiles à six rais sous un chef, à la bordure chargée de besants brochant&apos; - Inventaire des sceaux de Champagne, A. Coulon, Volume V: Papes, Cardinaux , Archevêques, évêques 1427-1602.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Albergati, Nicola</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Albergati1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a crucifix with a crown of thorns in the centre; on each arm, a nail; a plaque above with the inscription &apos;INRI&apos;; below, a nail at the base; below, in a niche, a man (cardinal), kneeling, facing right, hands raised, holding a book; on the left, a cardinal&apos;s hat with tasseled cords.</Design>
<Legend>S · NIChOLAI · TIT · CRVCI&apos; · Ī · IhERVSAL&apos; · PRESBITERI · CARDINALIS

[Sigillum Nicholai tituli Cruci in Iherusaleme Presbiteri Cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Croce in Gerusalemme</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1426</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Seal is unusual because the cardinal&apos;s hat is behind the kneeling cardinal, who appears to be praying in a niche between two spiral columns.  The foliate motifs on the ogival arch above seem to be Venetian.  Significantly there is no heraldry present.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Albret, Louis d&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>AlbretL1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In the spandrels on each side of a canopy, a half-length winged figure (angel); below, on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding indistinct objects in both hands; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man, standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; below, in an aedicule, a Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in a niche, a nimbed man (St John the Baptist), wearing a hair coat, holding a lamb in the left hand; on the right, in a niche, a nimbed man, standing, holding a palm leaf in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Heraldry>Chacon col. 1214, A.1461.</Heraldry>
<Legend>S · D · L · TT · STOM · PETRI &amp; MARCELLINI · PBRI · CARDINALIS · DE · LEBRE . . . 

[Sigillum Domini Ludovici Tituli Sanctorum Petri et Marcellini Presbiteri Cardinalis de Lebreto]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. Marcellino e Pietro</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1461</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Amboise, Georges d&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Amboise1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>Below a canopy, on the left, the Virgin sitting, full face, holding the dead Christ, sitting, facing half-right; on the right a man (cardinal), kneeling, facing left, hands raised, held together; behind, on the right, a man (St John the Baptist), standing, full face, holding a lamb in the right hand; below, on the left a shield of arms surmounted by a cross; on the right a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Heraldry>Two lions passant guardant in pale for Archiepiscopal Province of Rouen (left); paly of six, Amboise, ensigned with an archbishop&apos;s cross and cardinal&apos;s hat (right).
Chacon col. 1334, A.1500.  
McCarthy, v.1, p. 211, &apos;Arms,- Paly of six gules and or.&apos;</Heraldry>
<Legend>SIGILLVM · GEORGII · CARDINALIS : DE AMBASIA · ROTHOM · ARCHIEPI.

[Sigillum Georgii Cardinalis de Ambasia Rothomagensis Archiepiscopi]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Sisto</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1498</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>&apos;Rouen&apos;.  Horizontal lines above &apos;M&apos; in &apos;ROTHOM&apos; and &apos;P&apos; in &apos;ARCHIEPI&apos; in legend.  N.B. that the canopy is unusual at this date; the rib-vaulting is also shown.  There is no exergue: the shields float on the picture plane.  The border is quite wide.

Demay, G. &apos;Inventaire des Sceaux de la Normandie&apos;, no. 2156, p. 232.  Original held in Musée de Rouen.  &apos;Sceau détaché&apos;.

Alternative measurements: 85 x 65</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Aragona, Giovanni d&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>AragonJ1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>On a throne, the Virgin and Child sitting; on the left, a nimbed man standing, facing half-right; on the right, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, looking upwards, arms held behind the back; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Heraldry>Shield quartered: 1 and 4 Aragon, 2 and 3, three bundles, three birds in pale, cross of Jerusalem.

McCarthy, v.1, p. 198, &apos;Arms,- ARAGON quartering per pale HUNGARY, ANJOU Ancient and JEUSALEM [sic].&apos; [Or, four pallets gules quartering per pale Barry gules and argent impaling gules, from a triple mount vert, a patriarchal cross argent issuing from a coronet or, France ancient, a label of four points gules (often shown when quartered as three points) and Argent, a cross potent between four crosslets or].</Heraldry>
<Legend>SIGILLVM [ . . . ] IOANNIS · CARDINALIS [ . . . ] ARAGONIA

[Sigillum . . . Johannis Cardinalis . . . Aragonia]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Adriano</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1477</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Enthroned Madonna and Child design is unusual in use of three projecting circular bases for each saint.  Early use of asymmetrical balusters?  Narrow band for legend.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Barbo, Marco</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>BarboM1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In a pediment, on the left, a nimbed and winged figure (angel), kneeling, facing right; on the right, the Virgin, sitting, full face, hands across the chest;  a flower on a stem in a pot between; below, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Mark?) standing, full face, holding a palm or quill in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand;  on the left, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; on the right, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; below, the names of the three figures are inscribed on the divider, though indistinct; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, full face, hands raised, held together; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S MARCI BARBO : TT S MARCI : PSBRI CARDINALIS VENETIA EPI VICENTINI DVCIS COMITIS &amp; MARCHIONIS

[S. Marci Barbo, tituli Sancti Marci presbyteri cardinalis Venetiarum, episcopi Vicentini, duci, comitis et marchionis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Marco</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1467</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;Barbo (de Venise), / qui sont [d’azur] au lion [d’argent] lampassé [de gueules] à la bande [d’or] brochant. / Suivant les règles de la courtoisie héraldique le lion, sur l’écu dextre, est con- / tourné et la bande est remplacée par une barre.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Barbo, Marco</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>BarboM2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length Virgin and Child; the Christ Child holding a a globe; on the left, in a niche, a nimbed man, half-length, facing half-right, holding an indistinct object in the left hand; on the right a nimbed man, half-length, facing half-left, holding a sword in the right hand and a book in the left hand (St Paul?); below, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Mark) sitting, facing half-right, writing on a pulpit with a winged lion, sitting, facing left; on the left, in an aedicule a nimbed and mitred man (St Hermagoras), standing, facing half-right, holding a cross-staff in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, holding a palm in the right hand and a book in the left hand; below, the names of the figures are inscribed on the divider: &apos;	S ERMAGO : S. MARCUS : S. FORTUN&apos;; below, an aedicule; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>MARCVS EPVS PRENESTINVS PATRIARCHA AQUILEIENSIS CARDINALIS S. MARCI

[Marcus episcopus Prenestinus patriarcha Aquilegensis et cardinalis S. Marci]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Palestrina</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1478</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . armes de Barbo ([d’azur] au lion [d’argent] lampassé [de gueules] à la bande [d’or] brochant), timbré d’un chapeau / à huit houppes.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Bar, Louis</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>BarL1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule a woman (St Agatha) standing, full face; on the left, a helmeted man standing, facing right, holding a pair of tongs to the woman&apos;s breast; on the right a man standing, facing left, holding a pair of tongs to the woman&apos;s breast; on the left, a nimbed man (St Mammes?) standing, full face, holding entrails, with a lion, sitting, facing right, on the left; on the right, a man (St Christopher), walking left through water, holding a staff in the right hand, carrying the Christ Child on the back; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . ]IACONI CARDIN[ . . ]IS ADMĪSTR[ . . . ]

[D]iaconi cardin[al]is administr[atoris]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Agata</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1397</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Arms of Bar, France.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Bar, Louis</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>BarL2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length Virgin and Child; on each side, in an aedicule, a nimbed and winged figure (angel), facing inwards, a hand on the chest; below, on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, facing half-right, holding a book in the right hand and a staff in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, hands raised, holding an indistinct object; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Mammes?) standing, full face, holding entrails, with a lion, sitting, facing right, on the left; on the right, in aedicule, a nimbed man (St Christopher), walking left through water, holding a staff in the right hand, carrying the Christ Child on the back; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>s ludovici de barro basilice duod [ . . . ] ostolorum presbiteri cardinalis

[Sigillum Ludovici de Barro, basilice duodecim Apostolorum presbiteri cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. XII Apostoli</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1409</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . deux écus écartelés de Bar et de France&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Note that the coats of arms have changed in this seal.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Bessarion</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Bessarion1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed and winged figure (angel), standing, full face, arms across the chest; on the right, in an aedicule, a man (St John the Baptist), standing, facing half-left, wearing a hair coat; below, in a niche, a mitred male figure (cardinal); on the left, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ]NEN · CARDI · NICENI

[episcopi Sabi]nensis cardinalis Niceni</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sabina</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1449</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . [d’or] à un dextro- / chère et un senestrochère opposés, mouvants des flancs, parés et rebrasseés / [de gueules], les mains [de carnation], tenant ensemble une croix tréflée / au pied fiché [de gueules], le tout accompagné en chef de sept nuées [d’arg- / gent] 3 et 4, desquelles jaillissent des rayons de soleil [d’or], chaque / nuée chargée d’une étoile [d’or]. &apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Blau, Pierre</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>BlauP1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the crucified Christ; below, in an aedicule, a nimbed and winged figure (St Michael) standing, holding a cross-staff, transfixing a serpent or dragon lying on its side; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S’ PETRI : DEI : GRACIA : SCI : ANGELI : DIACONI : CARDINALIS

[Sigillum Petri, Dei gracia Sancti Angeli diaconi cardinalis].</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Angelo</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1395</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Lion rampant</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Brogny, Jean Allarmet de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Brunhiac1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin lying on her side; above, in a manger, the Christ Child, lying on his back, above, the head of an ass or donkey, and on the right, the head of an ox; below, in an aedicule, a nimbed woman standing, facing half-left, holding a palm in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the left, a man (cardinal), kneeling, facing right, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, in an aedicule, a winged figure (angel), facing inwards, a hand on the chest; below, a shield of arms supported by two lions, surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S · IOhANIS · CA[ . . . ] EN · S · RO · ECCE · VICECA

[Sigillum Iohannis Cardinalis Ostiensis Sancte Romane Ecclesie Vicecancellarius/Vicecamerarius]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Ostia e Velletri</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1405</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Double cross.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Horizontal abbreviation line above &apos;NIS&apos;, &apos;EN&apos; and final &apos;CA&apos;.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Calvillo, Ferdinando de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Calleville1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a figure standing, facing half-right; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, holding a sword in the right hand; around the border, in a series of aedicules, seven men, half-length, facing inwards, holding various attributes (apostles?); below, a nimbed and winged figure (angel), full face, placing a cardinal&apos;s hat above a shield of arms at each side of a niche; below, in the niche, a mitred man (cardinal), facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together.</Design>
<Heraldry>Two quartered shields: 1 and 4: foliate cross (&apos;gigliata&apos;), 2 and 3: bends.</Heraldry>
<Legend>[ . . . ]SILICE DV[ . . . ] APOSTOLORVM

[. . . Basilice Duodecim Apostolorum]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. XII Apostoli</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1397</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>none</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Campeggio, Lorenzo</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CampeggioL1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face holding a flowering rod or sceptre in the left hand; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man (St Osmund), standing, full face, raising the right hand in blessing and holding a crosier in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Andrew), standing, full face, holding a diagonal cross; below, the names of these figures are inscribed on the divider: &apos;OSMUND, MARIA, ANDREAS&apos;; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised and held together, a crosier held behind the right arm; on each side a shield of arms; below a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Heraldry>A cross staff in pale between a halved [eagle] and a rampant dog with a cardinal&apos;s hat in chief

Three leopards within a bordure, bearing three foils.</Heraldry>
<Legend>If any, lost</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Maria in Trastevere</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1528</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Very unusual style of seal.  Certainly not made in Italy as the canopied niches are more reminiscent of mid-15th-century examples.  As Campeggio was legate/collector, did he have a seal made that was deliberately &apos;English&apos;, or at least &apos;ultramontane&apos;?


Upper register was probably identical to that of CampeggioL1 as the inscription in the border and the drapery folds of the figures above appear to match.  May in fact be the same seal - this is just a fragment.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Capranica, Angelo de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CapranicaA1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, Christ crucified; below, in an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed figure standing, full face, holding a vase with a serpent(?) in the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Jerome) wearing a cardinal&apos;s hat, holding a book in his right hand; a lion standing, facing right, in front of the saint; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ] + [ . . . ]RLM PBRI CARDINALIS REATINI

[Tituli Sancte Crucis in Jerusalem presbiteri cardinalis Reatini.]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Croce in Gerusalemme</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1460</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . on y voit trois objets en fasce, rassemblant fort à des raies et retenus par un lien d&apos;où pend un crochet.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Carafa, Oliviero</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CarafaO1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, a nimbed and mitred man standing, facing half-right, holding a crosier in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the right, a nimbed man (St Peter) standing, facing half-left, holding a pair of keys in the left hand and a book in the right hand; below, a shield of arms surmounted by an archiepiscopal cross and a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ]NI + O[ . . ]VERII [ . . ]RRA[ . . ] [CAR]DINALIS + [ . . . ]NI

[S. domi]ni O[li]verii [Ca]rra[fa car]dinalis + Neapolitani</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. Marcellino e Pietro</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1467</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Carbone, Francesco</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CarboniF1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length Virgin and Child, holding a flowering rod or a sceptre in the right hand; below, in a niche, a nimbed woman (St Susanna?) standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and a book in the left hand.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . ]ESBITERI . CARDINAL[ . ]S .

[ . . . Presbiteri Cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Susanna</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1385</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>Illustrated and recorded in &apos;Fondo Certosini&apos; (Citta del Vaticano, 2004), Fondo Certosini, 4.  Noted that this seal does not appear in Sella.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Carvajal, Juan de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Carvajal1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length figure of the Virgin and Child; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man facing half-right, holding an indistinct object in the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man, half-length, full face, holding an indistinct object in the right hand; below, in a niche, an armoured nimbed and winged figure (St Michael), standing, full face, holding a cross-staff in the right hand, transfixing a serpent or dragon lying on its side below; on the left, in a niche, a nimbed man (St Peter) standing, facing half-right, holding a pair of keys in the right hand; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man, standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the right hand; on the right, in a niche, a nimbed man (St Paul) standing, facing half-left, holding a sword in the right hand; on the right, a nimbed man standing, full face, wearing a sunburst or star on the garments; below, in a niche, a man (cardinal) kneeling, full face, hands raised, held together; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>§ S · IO · DE · CARVAIAL · CARD · SCI · ANGELI §

[Sigillum Iohannis de Carvaial Cardinalis Sancti Angeli]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Angelo</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1446</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Two shields of arms: a bend, within a narrow bordure, for Carvajal, each ensigned with a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>&apos;§&apos; stands for foilate decoration in the legend.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Carvajal, Bernardino de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CarvajalB1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the right hand; on the right, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, holding an indistinct object in the right hand; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ]AL : T T S: CRVCIS IN IERVSA[ . . ] S : R : E: P[ . . . ]

[Carvaial : Tituli Sancte Crucis in Ierusaleme . . . Sancte Romane Ecclesie Presbiteri]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Croce in Gerusalemme</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1495</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Castiglione, Branda da</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CastiglioneB1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length Virgin and Child, full face; below, in a niche, on the left, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the right hand, wearing a papal tiara; on the right, a nimbed and mitred man, standing, full face, holding a whip or flail in his right hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man kneeling, facing left, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S&apos; · BRANDE · D&apos; CASTELLIONO · T · S · CLEMETIS · PBI · CARDIN&apos;

[Sigillum Brande de Castelliono tituli Sancti Clementis presbiteri cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Clemente</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1411</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>A lion carrying a castle?</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Demay, G., &apos;Inventaire des Sceaux de la Normandie&apos;, no. 2154, pp. 231-232.  Held in the Musée de Rouen.  &apos;Sceau détaché&apos;.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Challant, Antoine de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Challant1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, Christ sitting, the right hand raised in blessing and holding a globe in the right hand; below, in an aedicule, the the Virgin and Child sitting, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St John the Baptist), standing, facing half-right, holding a lamb in the left hand; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, holding a palm in the left hand and a book in the right hand; below, in a niche, a figure; on the right a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>If any, lost</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Maria in Via Lata</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1404</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Cibo, Innocenzo</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CiboI1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>God the Father sitting, holding the crucified Christ, with seven winged heads (cherubim) below, on the left and right; below, in a boat with an oar on water, the Virgin and Child sitting, full face, the Christ Child raising the right hand and holding a globe in the left hand; on the left a winged figure (angel), standing, full face, holding a candlestick; on the right, a winged figure (angel), holding a candlestick; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat; on the left, a head, facing left, looking downwards; on the right, a head, facing right, looking downwards.</Design>
<Legend>If any, lost.</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Maria in Domnica</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1517</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Castelnau de Clermont-Ludève, François de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>ClermontF1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In a lunette, a half-length figure, full face, indistinct; below, in an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, sitting on a plinth, facing half-right, looking downwards; on the right a man (cardinal), kneeling, facing left, hands raised, held together; behind, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, holding a crucifix in the right hand (St Francis?); below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ] MAGNV : R : D : FRANC[ . . . ] CLAR[ . . . ] [ . . . ] CELIOMONTE&apos; C[ . . . ] AVINION[ . . . ]

[Sigillum magnum Reverendissimi Domini Francisci Claromonte . . . Celiomonte Cardinalis Avinionensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Stefano al Monte Celio</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1509</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Coëtivy, Alain de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>CoetivyA1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed woman standing, full face, holding a sword in the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed woman standing, holding a chalice in the left hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, full face, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ] TI.  S. PRAXEDIS PBRI.  CARD. AVINIONEN. Z [ . . . ]

[. . . tituli sancte Praxedis presbiteri cardinalis Avinionensis et . . . ]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Prassede</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1449</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . deux écus d&apos;un fascé de six pièces.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>&apos;Z&apos; in legend may be an abbreviation of &apos;et&apos;.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Correr, Antonio</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Correr1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>Below a vaulted canopy with stars, Christ, levitating, full face, hands raised above the head, looking upwards; on each side, six nimbed men (apostles), kneeling, facing inwards; below, an inscription on the divider: &apos;TRAhE · DE · NOS Ī CE&apos; [Trahe de nos in Celum]; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, facing left, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms, the shield on the right surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S · [ . . ]TONII · CORARI .  ·[ . . ]ISC&apos;OPI · OSTIEN · CARDINALIS · BONON:

[Sigillum Antonii Corarii Episcopi Ostiensis Cardinalis Bononensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Ostia e Velletri</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1431</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Shield with the keys in decusse, on the left; rhombus truncated?</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Horizontal abbreviation line above &apos;DE&apos;.  Cardinal&apos;s hat only over family arms.  Martyr&apos;s palm leaf over the crossed keys?  Rib vaulting above includes stars.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Enckevoirt, Willem</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>EnckevoirtG1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length Christ, full face, hands raised; below, in an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man standing, facing half-right, holding a crosier in the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ] DE · ENCKENVOIRT · TI · S · IOA · ET · PAV · PRE

[ . . . de Enckenvoirt tituli Sanctorum Ioannis et Pauli Presbiteri]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. Giovanni e Paolo</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1523</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Sigillo in ceralacca rossa, ovale.
Traces of shellac in tin skippet and around cords.  Exact size of seal unknown but container measures 126 x 77 mm.  Cherubim present in micro-architecture &amp; details reminiscent of Wolsey&apos;s collegiate seals.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Epinay, André d&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>EpinayA1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, on the left, a nimbed man (St John the Baptist), standing, facing half-right, holding a lamb in the left hand; on the right, a nimbed man (St Andrew), standing, facing half-left, holding a diagonal cross; on the left, in an aedicule, a winged figure (angel) standing, facing half-right, holding a candlestick; on the right, in an aedicule, a winged figure (angel), facing half-left, holding a chalice; below, a shield of arms, surmounted by an archiepiscopal cross and a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S. d. CARDINALIS LVdVNNEN. ARCHIEPI BVRdEGALEN. GALLIARVMQ§ AQVITANIE PRIMATIS

[Sigillum domini cardinalis Ludunnensis archiepiscopi Burdegalensis Galliarumque Aquitanie primatis.]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. Silvestro e Martino ai Monti</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1489</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . un écu écartelé, au 1 et 4, d&apos;un lion couronné; au 2 et 3 de neuf merlettes à un lambel; sur le tout un écu indistinct.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>&apos;Lyon&apos;. &apos;§&apos; in legend stands for &apos;-UE&apos; Latin abbreviation.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Estouteville, Guillaume d&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>EstoutevilleG1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Martin) mounted on horse walking to left, cutting a cloak with a sword in the right hand; on the right, a man standing, facing left, looking upwards, hands raised and held together; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat; on each side, a head in a roundel.</Design>
<Legend>SG · TT S · MARTINI IN MONTIB[ . . . ] PBRI ·  CARD&apos; DE ESTOVTEVILLA

[Sigillum Guillelmi, tituli sancti Martini presbiteri cardinalis de Estoutevilla]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. Silvestro e Martino ai Monti</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1440</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . un écu écartelé, au 1 et 4 d&apos;Estouteville, au 2 et 3 d&apos;Harcourt, à un écusson sur le tout chargé de trois fleurs de lys brisées d&apos;un bâton.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Estouteville, Guillaume d&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>EstoutevilleG2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In the spandrels on each side of a canopy, a half-length winged figure (angel); below, on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed and armoured man standing, full face, holding indistinct object in the right hand and a globe in the left; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man, standing, full face, holding a cross-staff in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; below, in an aedicule, a Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in a niche, a nimbed man (St John the Baptist), wearing a hair coat, holding a lamb in the left hand; on the right, in a niche, a nimbed woman standing, holding a palm leaf in the right hand and a chalice in the left hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S G · EPI · OST[ . . . ] [ . . . ]VILLA · ARCHIEPI · ROTHOMAGEN ·

[Sigillum Guillelmi episcopi Ostiensis, cardinalis de Estoutevilla, archiepiscopi Rothomagensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Ostia e Velletri</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1461</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . un écu écartelé, au 1 et 4 d&apos;Estouteville, au 2 et 3 d&apos;Harcourt, à un écusson sur le tout chargé de trois fleurs de lys brisées d&apos;un bâton.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Fieschi, Lodovico</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>FieschiL1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length Virgin and Child, full face; below, in a niche, a nimbed woman standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>+ S&apos;: LUDOUICI: D&apos; FLISCO: STI: ADRIANI: DIACONI: CARDINALIS

[Sigillum Ludovici de Flisco Sancti Adriani Diaconi Cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Adriano</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1385</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Three bends</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Horizontal abbreviation line above &apos;STI&apos;.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Fieschi, Nicola</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>FieschiN1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a half-length figure; below, in an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a staff in the left hand and an indistinct object in the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, figure standing, full face, holding an indistinct object; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S · NICOLAI · TIT · S · LVCIE · IN SEPTEM SOLIO [ . . . ] S · R · E · [ . . . ] · CARDINALIS · DE · FLISCO

[Sigillum Nicolai tituli Sancte Lucie in Septem Solio . . . Sancte Romane Ecclesie Cardinalis de Flisco]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Lucia in Septizonio</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1503</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Three bends
Sigillo in ceralacca rossa, ovale.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Sigillo in ceralacca rossa, ovale.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Foix, Pierre de (Elder)</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>FoixP2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, sitting, full face, holding an indistinct object; on each side, a winged figure (angel), facing inwards, one hand on chest; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; a shield of arms on each side surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S · dni [ . . . ] cardinalis · de · fu[ . . ] [ . . . ] albanensis

[Sigillum domini Petri, cardinalis de Fuxo, episcopi Albanensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Albano</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1431</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos; . . . deux écus à trois pals écartelés de deux vaches passant l&apos;une sur l&apos;autre, timbrés d&apos;un chapeau de cardinal.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Givry, Claude de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Givry1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, the right hand raised to chest, holding entrails in his left hand, with a lion, standing, full face, below; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man standing, full face, holding a cross-staff in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed woman (St Agnes?) standing, full face, holding a book in the right hand and a palm in the left hand, with a lamb, standing on its hind legs, facing right, below; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>SIGILLV : MAGNVM : DOMINI : CARDINALIS : DE : GIVRY : TITVLI : SANCTE : AGNETIS : IN : AGONE

[Sigillum Magnum Domini Cardinalis de Givry tituli Sancte Agnetis in Agone]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Agnese in Agone</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1533</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Arms of Longuy.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Illustrated in &apos;Recueil des Sceaux du Moyen Age&apos;, plate VII, 2 and noted p. 14 as Cardinal de Givry. &quot;Pinna dorsale sagomata e forata.&quot; - Bargello Cat.
BM matrix is suspect: chain loop is crude and the plate shallow for the period.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Gonzaga, Ercole</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>GonzagaE1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>The Virgin, sitting on a cloud, hands raised; on each side, a winged figure (angel), flying, facing inwards; below, a winged head (cherub); below, a figure group: on the left, two men standing, facing right, looking upwards; a man standing full face, looking downwards; a man kneeling, facing half-right, looking upwards, holding a book in the right hand; in the centre, an open sarcophagus with flowers inside; on the left, a man standing, facing half-left, looking downwards; a man standing, facing half-left, looking downwards, pointing into the sarcophagus with the right hand; a man standing, facing left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; a man kneeling, facing half-left, looking upwards, holding a book under the left arm (apostles); below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[HER · GONZAGA S · MARIAE DIAC · CAR · MANTVAN = Hercules Gonzaga Sanctae Mariae Diaconi Cardinalis Mantuanensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Maria Nuova</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1527</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Arms of the Gonzaga</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Briçonnet, Guillaume</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Guillaume1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man standing, full face, holding a book in the right hand and a cross-staff in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed figure standing, full face, holding a staff or sceptre in the right hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, faing half-left, holding a cross-staff under the right arm, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by an archiepiscopal cross and a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>pbteri i[ . . . ] francie

[presbiteri i. . . francie]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Pudenziana</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1495</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;. . . un écu écartelé d&apos;une fleur de lys à chaque quartier, à sénestre d&apos;un écu à la bande componée chargée et accompagnée d&apos;une étoile en chef . . . &apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Demay, G., &apos;Inventaire des Sceaux de la Flandre&apos;, vol. 2, no. 5755, p. 103.  Original held in Arch. du Nord ; évêché de chapitre de Cambrai.  &apos;Envoi de commissaires à l&apos;abbaye de Cysoing pour y prendre des mesures énergiques contre le relâchement des moeurs et le mauvais emploi de revenu. - 1er juin 1498.&apos;</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Cervantes, Juan de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Jean1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the right hand; on the left a nimbed and mitred man standing, full face, holding a cross-staff in the right hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, facing half-left, hands raised, held together; on the right, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>s&apos; ioh . . . . . incu . .  . . . . . Lis

[Sigillum Johannis, tituli Sancti Petri in Vincula presbiteri cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Pietro in Vincoli</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1426</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;. . . écus à deux biches passant l&apos;une sur l&apos;autre . . . &apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Demay, G., &apos;Inventaire des Sceaux de la Flandre&apos;, vol. 2, no. 5752, p. 103.  Original in Arch. du Nord ; chapitre de Saint-Amé.  &apos;Lettres de provision pour la chapellenie de Ransart. - 5 octobre 1441.&apos;</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Lagier, Bertrand</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Lagier2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, half-length, sitting on a bench, full face; below, in an an aedicule on the left, a nimbed man (St Francis?) standing, full face, blessing with the right hand and holding a cross in the left hand; on the right, a nimbed woman (St Cecily?) standing, facing half-left, holding a palm in the right hand; below, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, facing half -right, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms.</Design>
<Heraldry>Lion rampant</Heraldry>
<Legend>S: FR[ . . . ] [ . ]ETRADI: DEI: GRA: EPI: OSTIEN: ET: UELLETREN: CARD ·

[Sigillum Fratris Bertrandi Dei Gratia Episcopi Ostiensis et Velletrensis Cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Ostia e Velletri</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1378</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Le Jeune, Jean</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>LeJeune1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St John the Baptist) standing, full face, holding a lamb in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed figure (St Praxedis?) standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the right hand; below, in an niche, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, full face, hands raised, held together; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ]sce pr[ . . . ] cardinalis morinensis [ . . . ]

[ . . . Sancte Praxedis . . . Cardinalis Morinensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Prassede</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1440</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>A shield quartered: 1 and 4 a fleur de lys dans les clairevoies; aux 2 et 3, trois fasces chargées , la première de 3, la deuxième de 2, la troisième de 1 coquille ; chaque écu surmonté d&apos;un chapeau à glands, supporté par un lion accroupi.?
Bourgogne no. 877.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Lenzol-Borgia, Rodrigo</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Lenzol-BorgiaR1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man (St Nicholas) standing, full face, holding a crosier under the right arm and a book in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed and armoured figure (St Michael), standing, facing half-right, looking downwards, holding a staff in the right hand and a shield in the left hand; below, an inscription in the divider: &apos;. . . S NIC . . . &apos;; below, an aedicule; on the left a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ] R.  CARD.  VALEN.  S. RO. E. VICECAN

[Rodericus Cardinalis Valentinus Sancte Romane Ecclesie vicecancellarius]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Nicola in Carcere</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1456</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;De chaque coté, un écu à ses / armes : parti au 1, un taureau ; au 2, deux fasces, timbré d’un chapeau à / six houppes.&apos;

&apos;Sous un triple portique de style Renaissance, trois saints debout, / de face, nimbés.  Au milieu, Saint Nicolas, mitré, la crosse dans la main droi- / te, en biais, volute en dedans, un livre dans la main gauche; à gauche, Saint- / Sébastien nu ; à droite, saint-Michel perçant le dragon de sa lance.  Leur / nom est inscrit en abrégé sur le soubassement : S. SEB (Sanctus Sebastianus) / - S.NIC (Sanctus Nicolaus) – S. MI. . (Sanctus Michaël).  Au-dessus, dans trois / niches plus petites, à coquille, au centre la Vierge à mi-corps, nimbée, / de face, tenant l’Enfant Jésus nimbé sur son bras droit.  A gauche et à / droite, deux saints nimbés, de face, en buste.  Celui de gauche paraît être / un moine.  A la partie inférieure du sceau, dans une petite niche à fronton, le cardinal agenouillé, de face et priant.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Also listed in G. Navarro, &apos;Catalogo de Sellos&apos;, vol. 2, pp. 169-70.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Longueil, Richard-Olivier de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>LongueilRO1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule on the left, a nimbed man (St Peter), half-length, facing half-right, holding a key in the left hand and an indistinct object in the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Paul), half-length, facing half-left, holding a sword in the right hand; below, in an aedicule, the Virgin and Child standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed, winged and armoured figure (St Michael) standing, full face, holding a cross-staff, transfixing a serpent or dragon that is lying on its back; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man standing, facing half-left, blessing with the right hand, holding a crosier in the left hand; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>sigillum ricardi cardinalis constanciensis

[Sigillum Ricardi Cardinalis  Constanciensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Eusebio</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1462</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;. . . d&apos;un écartelé, au 1 et de 4, trois quitefeuilles mises en fasce; au 2 et 3, de deux quitefeuilles accompagnées d&apos;un lion passant, en chef, à dextre.&apos;
&apos;Constance&apos;.  Dans une niche principale, la Vierge avec l&apos;enfant Jésus, debout, vue de face, couronnée et nimbée; à sa droite, l&apos;archange saint Michel terrassant le démon, et à l&apos;étage supérieur saint Pierre à mi-corps.  A sa gauche, un saint évêque mitré, crossé et bénissant, et à l&apos;étage supérieur saint Paul à mi-corps.  Au bas, un écu timbré d&apos;un chapeau de cardinal; d&apos;un écartelé, au 1 et de 4, trois quitefeuilles mises en fasce; au 2 et 3, de deux quitefeuilles accompagnées d&apos;un lion passant, en chef, à dextre.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Lusignan, Hugues de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>LusignanH1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>Christ standing, full face, hands raised; on the left, a man (Elijah) standing, facing half-right, looking upwards, hands raised, clasped; on the right, a man (Moses) standing, facing half-left, looking upwards, hands raised and held together; below, a man sitting, full face; on the left, a nimbed man sitting, facing half-right, hands raised; on the right, a man lying on the back, looking upwards, the right hand raised (Sts Peter, James and John); below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal)  kneeling, full face, hands raised, held together; on each side a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>sigillum · hugonis · episc[ . . . ] pre[ . . . ] [ . . . ]nalis · cipri

[Sigillum Hugonis, episcopi Prenestrini cardinalis Cipri]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Palestrina</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1431</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>&apos;deux écus écartelés, au 1, d’une croix potencée  cantonée de quatre croisettes et chargée en cœur de . . . .  au 2, 3 et 4 d’un lion, timbrés d’un chapeau de cardinal.  Champ festonné.&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Maramaldo, Landolfo</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Maramaldo1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, half-length, full face; below, in a niche, a nimbed and mitred man (St Nicholas?) sitting, full face, blessing with the right hand and holding a crosier in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed figure, half-length(?), facing half-left, holding an indistinct object in the left hand; below, in a niche, a man kneeling, full face, hands raised, held together; on the left a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S&apos; · LANDVLFI · DEI · GRACIA . . .  CARDINALIS · [ . . ]RENSIS

[Sigillum Landulfi Dei Gracia . . . Cardinalis Barensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Nicola in Carcere</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1381</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Three bends with a border &apos;cuneata&apos;</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Foliage intrudes into legend at top left.  Large seal for the period - close in size to examples from the sixteenth century.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Medici, Giulio de&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>MediciG1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>God the Father, half-length, facing half-left, looking downwards; below, a dove (Holy Spirit); below, in the background, an arcade and landscape beyond; in front, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and a book in the right hand and a grid iron under the right arm (St Lawrence); below, on the right, the Virgin kneeling, facing half-left, looking downwards, hands raised, held together; on the left, the Christ Child, lying against a cushion; on the left, a nimbed man (St Paul) standing, facing half-right, holding a sword in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the right a nimbed man (St Peter) standing, facing half-left, holding a pair of keys in th right hand and a book in the left hand; behind, a group of figures, some playing instruments; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat, surpported on each side by winged figure flying, facing inwards (angel).</Design>
<Legend>IV : TT S LAV:IN.DAM:DIA CAR.DE.MED:S:R:E: VICECAN · THVSCIAE · BON[ . . . ] LEGAT

[Iulius Tituli Sancti Laurentii in Damaso Diaconus Cardinalis De Medicis Sancte Romane Ecclesie Vicecancellarius Thusciae Bonensis Legatus]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Lorenzo in Damaso</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1517</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Six palle: arms of the Medici
Presumed presentation model by Lautizio da Perugia.  Ex-collection Heinz Schneirder, on loan to Ashmolen Museum, Oxford.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Medici, Giulio de&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>MediciG2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In a lunette, a God the Father, half-length, full face, blessing with the right hand; below, in an aedicule, a dove (Holy Spirit); on the left, a nimbed child (St John the Baptist) standing, facing half-right, holding a banner; at the child&apos;s feet is the Christ Child, lying on the back; on the right, the Virgin, kneeling, facing half-left, hands raised, held together; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>IV : CAR : DE MEDICIS BON : [ . . . ]N: LEGAT

[Iulius Cardinalis de Medicis Bononensis . . . Legatus]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Maria in Domnica</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1514</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Six palle, arms of the Medici.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Legate of Bologna.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Medici, Ippolito de&apos;</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>MediciI1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>God the Father, half-length, facing half-left, looking downwards; below, a dove (Holy Spirit); below, in the background, an arcade and landscape beyond; in front, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and a book in the right hand and a grid iron under the right arm (St Lawrence); below, on the right, the Virgin kneeling, facing half-left, looking downwards, hands raised, held together; on the left, the Christ Child, lying against a cushion; on the left, a nimbed man (St Paul) standing, facing half-right, holding a sword in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the right a nimbed man (St Peter) standing, facing half-left, holding a pair of keys in th right hand and a book in the left hand; behind, a group of figures, some playing instruments; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat, supported on each side by winged figure flying, facing inwards (angel).</Design>
<Legend>HIP · TT : S : LAV : IN . DAM : DIA CAR. DE. MED : S : R : E : VICECAN : PERV : VMBR · Q . ZC : LEGAT :

[Hippolitus tituli Sancti Laurentii in Damaso Diaconus Cardinalis De Medicis Sancte Romane Ecclesie Vicecancellarius Perusie Umbriaque Etc. Legatus]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Lorenzo in Damaso</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1532</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Six palle, arms of the Medici</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Seal matrix of Giulio de&apos; Medici (1517-21) reused by Ippolito.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Mella, Juan de</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>MellaJ1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In a niche, the Virgin and Child, half-length, full face; on each side, in an aedicule, a nimbed and winged figure (angel) standing, full face; below, in a niche, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; on the left, in a niche, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a lamb in the left hand; on the right, in a niche, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a staff in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, full face, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S · IO · TI · SCE · PRISCE · P[ . . . ] CARDINALIS · ZAMOR[ . . . ]

[Sigillum Johannis, Tituli Sancte Prisce Presbiteri Cardinalis Zamorensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Prisca</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1456</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Michieli, Giovanni</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>MichieliG2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child standing, full face; on the left, a nimbed man (St John the Baptist) standing, facing half-right, holding a lamb in the left hand; on the right a nimbed man, standing, wearing a cardinal&apos;s hat (St Jerome).</Design>
<Legend>S : IO : SCTE [ . . . ] [ . . . ]CONI CARDINALIS V[ . ]NETIS :
[Sigillum Johannis Sancte Lucie . . . Diaconi Cardinalis Venetis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Lucia in Septizonio</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1468</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>Douet d&apos;Arcq, &apos;Inventaire des sceaux&apos; 6212.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Montferrato, Teodoro di</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>MontferratT1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule on the left, a nimbed man standing, full face; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the left hand; below, in an aedicule, on the left, a nimbed and winged figure (Archangel Gabriel) kneeling, facing right, looking upwards, blessing with the right hand, holding a flower on a stem in the left hand; on the right, the Virgin, sitting, facing half-left, hands raised to chest; below, in a niche, a nimbed man standing, holding a staff in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat supported by a nimbed and winged figure (angel), half-length, full face.</Design>
<Legend>S&apos; * TEO[ . . . ] [ . . . ] SCI TEODORI [ . . . ] CA

[Sigillum Teodori . . . Sancti Teodori . . . Cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Teodoro</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1468</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>Unusual placement of a saint in the lower niche.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Orsini, Franciotto</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>OrsiniF1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, half-length, full face; below an inscription: &apos;S. GEORGIVS&apos;; below, in an aedicule, a nimbed man holding a lance in the right hand mounted on a horse galloping to the left; on the left, a dragon sitting, transfxied by the lance; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat; on each side, a cornucopia.</Design>
<Legend>FRANCIOTTVS · S · GEORGII · S · R · [ . ] · DIACONVS · CARDINALIS · VRSINVS ·

[Franciottus Sancti Georgii Sancte Romane Ecclesie Diaconus Cardinalis Ursinus]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Giorgio in Velabro</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1517</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>A rose, a bundle, three bends.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Design possibly related to the legatine seal of Giulio de&apos; Medici.  Micro-architectural framework serves as an imitation altarpiece.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Orsini, Giordano</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>OrsiniG1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal bishop</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, Christ crucified, full face; below, in an aedicule, a nimbed and mitred man standing, full face, holding a crosier in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the left, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a grid-iron in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the right, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the right hand and a palm in the left hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, full face, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S’ DNI · IORDANI · EPI · ALBAN [ . . . ] [ . . . ]NE · ECC’ · CARD’ · DE VRSINI’

[Sigillum Domini Iordani Episcopi Albanensis Sancte Romane Ecclesie Cardinalis De Ursini]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Albano</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1412</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Dans une niche principale, trois personnages nimbés et debout : celui du milieu mitré, crossé, tenant un livre; celui de dextre tête nue, tenant une grille et un livre; celui de sénestre couronné, tenant un écu au lion et une palme.  Dans une niche supérieure, le Christ en croix; au bas, le cardinal priant, accosté de deux écus bandés de six pièces au chef chargé d’une rose? et timbrés d’un chapeau de cardinal.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Panciera, Antonio</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Panciera1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a nimbed and crowned woman standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand and a book in the left hand (St Susanna?); below, in an aedicule, a man (cardinal) kneeling, facing left, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S. D. ANTONII . TIT&apos; . S. SUSANE PBRI CARD . AQLEGE

[Sigillum Domini Antonii Tituli Sancte Susanne Presbiteri Cardinalis Aquilegensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Susanna</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1411</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>A bend . . .</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Bourgogne no. 874</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Petrucci, Alfonso</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Petrucci1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an roundel, God the Father, half-length, blessing with his right hand, holding a globe in the left hand; on each side, a winged figure (angel or putto) sitting on an entablature, facing outwards, holding a festoon; below, in an aedicule, on the left, the Virgin and Child sitting on a pedestal, facing half-right, looking downwards; on the right, a nimbed man (St Theodore?) standing, facing half-left, holding a feather or a palm in the right hand; below, a man (cardinal) kneeling, facing left, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>SIGILLVM  ALFONSI · PETRVCII · SENEN · S · THEODORI · DIACONI ·  CARDINALIS ·

[Alfonsi Petrucii Senensis Sancti Theodori Diaconi Cardinalis Sigillum]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Teodoro</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1511</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Arms of Petrucci</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Amiel, Pierre</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Pierre1</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a nimbed man (St Mark), sitting on a bench, facing half-left, writing in a book; on the left, a mitred man (cardinal), kneeling, full face, looking upwards, hands raised, holding the book; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed and winged figure (angel) kneeling, facing right, lessing with the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a winged lion sitting, facing left; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat; on the left an indistinct animal; on the right, a lion (?) crouching, facing half-left.</Design>
<Legend>sigillu . petri misericordia d. tt. sci. marci pbri. card.

[Sigillum Petri, misericordia Dei/divina tituli sancti Marci presbiteri cardinalis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Marco</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1378</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Dans une niche gothique, à droite un personnage nimbé, assis et écrivant sur un livre, que tient un évêque à genoux devant lui.  Dans deux loges : à droite le lion de saint Marc, à gauche un ange.  Au bas, un écu chargé de trois croissants.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>The coat of arms is problematic: see Font-Reaulx, cat. no. 153.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Pisani, Francesco</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>PisaniF1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>On a pedestal, Christ, half-length, full face; below, in an aedicule, the Virgin and Child standing, full face; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a lamb the left hand (St John the Baptist); on the right, in an aedicule, a mitred and nimbed man standing, full face, holding a crosier in the left hand and a book in the right hand; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S · FRANCISCI · SANCTE · MARIE · IN PO[ . . . ] [ . . ]ACONI · CARDINALIS · PISANI

[Sigillum Francisci Sancte Marie in Porticu Diaconi Cardinalis Pisani]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Maria in Portico</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1528</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>A griffin.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Possibly related to the legatine seal of Giulio de&apos; Medici - the position of the shield, legend and hat are similar.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Pisani, Francesco</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>PisaniF2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>God the Father, half-length, facing half-left, raising the right hand and holding a book in the left hand; below, four winged heads (cherubim); below, the Virgin and Child sitting on a throne, full face; on the left, a nimbed man standing, facing half-right, holding a book in both hands; on the right, a nimbed and mitred man standing, facing half-left, holding a crosier in the right hand and an urn in the left hand; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat; on each side, foliate decoration.</Design>
<Legend>FRANCISCVS · S · MARCI · S · R · E · DIACONI · CARDINALIS · PISANVS · EPISC · PADVAN ·

[Franciscus Sancti Marci Sancte Romane Ecclesie Diaconi Cardinalis Pisanus Episcopus Paduanensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Marco</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1527</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>Note error in DEACON - S. MARCO was presbyterial.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Riario, Raffaele</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>RiarioR2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>A winged head (cherub); below, a nimbed and armoured man (St George), holding a lance in the right hand, mounted on a horse, facing right, impaling a dragon, standing, facing left; below, an archiepiscopal cross and a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Giorgio in Velabro</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1479</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Seriously damaged.  Variation on the design with the matrix in the Palazzo di Venezia.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Rolin, Jean</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>RolinJ1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, half-length, full face, on each side, in an aedicule, a nimbed and winged figure, facing inwards, below, in a niche, a nimbed man standing, holding a palm and an indistinct object in the left hand; on the left, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand; on the right, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a crosier in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . ]hannis · roli[ . . . ] · et · epi · eduen

[ . . . Johannis Rolin . . . et episcopi Eduensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Stefano al Monte Celio</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1449</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Demay, G. &apos;Inventaire des Sceaux de la Normandie&apos;, no 2155, p. 232.  Held in Arch. De la Seine-Inférieure ; Jacobins.  &apos;Bulle d&apos;indulgences - Juin 1478&apos;.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Della Rovere, Giuliano</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>RovereG2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a figure kneeling or sitting, facing half-left; below, in an aedicule, on the left a nimbed man (St Peter) walking to right, facing half-right, hands raised and chained; on the right, a nimbed and winged figure (angel) standing, facing half-left, removing chains from the man&apos;s hands; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ] AD · VINCVLA · PRERI · CARD[ . . . ] 

[Sancti Petri ad Vincula Presbiteri Cardinalis . . . ]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Pietro in Vincoli</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1471</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Similar to the previous design.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Salviati, Giovanni</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>SalviatiG2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>The Virgin standing, full face, hands raised, held together, surrounded by ten winged heads (cherubim); below, in an aedicule, a nimbed man (St John the Baptist) standing, facing half-left, holding a cross-staff in the left hand and blessing with the right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a scalpel in the right hand and a book in the left hand; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a container in the left hand (Sts Cosmas and Damian); below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>IOANNES · S · COSME · ET · DAMIANI · DI · CAR · PRIN · ET EPS · FIRMANVS DE · SALVIATIS

[Ioannes Sanctorum Cosme et Damiani Domini Cardinalis Prin[?] et Episcopus Firmanus de Salviatis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. Cosma e Damiano</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1517</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>The arms of Salviati quartered with those of the Medici.
&quot;Piatta, a navetta.., sul dorso i resti della saldatura di un manico&quot; - Bargello Cat.</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Sommariva, Angelo de Anna</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Sommariva1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child, half-length, full face, holding a palm in the right hand; below, in a niche, a nimbed woman standing, full face, holding a palm in the right hand; on the left, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding an indistinct object in the left hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed woman standing, full face; below, in a niche, a mitred man (cardinal) kneeling, full face, looking upwards, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S&apos; angeli de anna titvli sce pvtentiane : peri cardinalis : laudensis

[Sigillum Angeli de Anna Tituli Sancte Putentiane Presbiteri Cardinalis Laudensis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Pudenziana</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1396</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>In chief, three lillies, three bends</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>Horizontal abbreviation line above &apos;RI&apos;.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Della Valle, Andrea</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Valle1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>God the Father sitting, holding the crucified Christ between his knees; below, in front of a building, two men standing, facing right, one with hands raised, held together, carrying a cross; on the right a mitred man standing, full face, holding a book and a woman standing, facing half-left, looking downwards, holding a palm in the left hand; in front of these figures, on the right, the Virgin and Child sitting on a plinth, facing half-left; on the left, a man kneeling, facing right, receiving an indistinct object from the Christ Child with the right hand; on the left, a man (St Sebastian) standing, full face, hands helds behind the back, an arrow on the ground in front of him; below, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat, supported by a winged figure (angel or putto) on each side.</Design>
<Heraldry>Two lions rampant combatant, betw. five estoiles, three in chief, two betw. the lions, in pale, on a chief a demi-eagle rising, issuing, crowned.</Heraldry>
<Legend>* ANDREAS * TT * S · PRISCAE * * PRES * CARD * DE * VALLE *

[Andreas tituli Sancte Priscae Presbiteri Cardinalis de Valle]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Prisca</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1525</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Vich, Guillen-Ramon</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Vich1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>The Virgin and Child sitting, facing half-right; on the right, a nimbed man kneeling, facing left, holding a container in the right hand; above, a man standing, full face, holding a staff or a spear in the left hand; on the left a nimbed man standing, facing half-right, leaning on a staff; above, a group of men standing, some playing musical instruments; on the right, a nimbed man kneeling, facing half-left, holding a container in both hands; above, a man, standing, facing half-left; on the right, a nimbed man standing, facing half-left, holding a container in the right hand; behind, on the right, two men standing, facing half-left and the head of a horse; on the left, a building with eight columns, an entablature, pediment and roof; above, a star; below the scene, a shield of arms surounted by  cardinal&apos;s hat; supported on each side an armoured man leaning and facing inwards.</Design>
<Legend>If any, lost</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Marcello</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1517</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Arms of Vich</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>none</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Viterbo, Egidio da</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Viterbo1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>The Virgin and Child sitting on a throne, full face; on the left, a nimbed and mitred man (St Augustine) standing, full face, holding a book in the right hand and a crosier under the left arm; on the right, a nimbed man (St Nicholas of Tolentino) standing, full face, holding a flower on a stem in the right hand and an indistinct object in the left hand; below, the names of the figures inscribed on the divider: &apos;S * AVGVSTINVS&apos; and &apos;S * NICOLAVS TOL&apos;; below, a shield of arms surmounted by an archiepiscopal cross and a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Heraldry>On three mounts or a tertre, a cross betw. two smaller crosses of which the arms are set obliquely, all forming a Hill of Calvary; above the shield, a cross fleury.</Heraldry>
<Legend>EGIDIVS · CAR · TT · S · MATTHEI · SANCTE · APOSTOLICE · SEDIS · DE LATERE · LEGATVS

[Egidius Cardinalis Tituli Sancti Matthei Sancte Apostolice Sedis De Latere Legatus]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>S. Matteo in Merulana</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1517</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>&quot;A fine example of Italian art, and may be compared with the seal of Cardinal Andreas de Valle.&quot; - Birch.

The Virgin with Christ Child enthroned with St Augustine as with crozier and book on the right; St Nicholas of Tolentino wih lily branch and staff with radiated estoile on the left.  Names of these saints inscribed on the plinth below.  Throne has shelll back with dome and lantern supported on Corinthian columns.  Sides in form of seated lions.  In base on corbel a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.  Carved borders.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Wolsey, Thomas</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Wolsey1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a vase; below, in an aedicule on the left, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a pair of keys in te right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a sword in the right hand; below, a shield of arms surmouted by an archiepiscopal cross and a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>[ . . . ]LLIV[ . ] [. . . ]OME [. . . ]DI[ . . . ] [ . . ]GATI · DE · LATE [ . . . ]

[Sigillum Thome Cardinalis Legati de Latere . . . ]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Cecilia in Trastevere</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1518</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>On a cross engrailed a lion passant betw. Four leopards&apos; heads cabossed, on a chief a rose betwe. two Cornish choughs, WOLSEY.

&apos;Legate a latere&apos;.  § in legend stands for five-petalled flower.?</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Wolsey, Thomas</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Wolsey2</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal priest</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, a vase; below, in an aedicule on the left, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a pair of keys in te right hand; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing, full face, holding a sword in the right hand; below, a shield of arms surmounted by an archiepiscopal cross and a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Heraldry>On a cross engrailed a lion passant betw. Four leopards&apos; heads cabossed, on a chief a rose betwe. two Cornish choughs, WOLSEY.</Heraldry>
<Legend>§ SIGILLIUM · THOME EBORACEN · MISERTIONE · DIVINA · CARDINALIS · ANGLIE.

[Sigillium Thome Miseratione Divina Cardinalis Anglie]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Cecilia in Trastevere</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1515</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Notes>§ in legend represents a flower with five petals.

A copy of British Museum cat. no. 2338 with numerous slight differences in the details.  The fluting of the pilasters omitted. A crozier inserted behind the shield below the cardinal&apos;s hat, and the tassels of the at differently arranged.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Zabarella, Francesco</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>Zabarella2</Identifier>
<Status>pseudocardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin and Child sitting on a throne, full face, holding a flower on a stem in the left hand; on the left, in an aedicule, a man standing, facing half-right, holding indistinct objects in both hands; on the right, in an aedicule, a nimbed man standing , facing half-left, holding an indistinct object in the left hand; below, in a niche, a mitred man kneeling, facing half-left, hands raised, held together; on each side, a shield of arms surmounted by a cardinal&apos;s hat.</Design>
<Legend>S · dni · francisci · cosme · et · dam [ . . . ] cardinalis · florentini

[Sigillum Domini Francisci Sanctorum Cosme et Damiani Cardinalis Florentini]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>SS. Cosma e Damiano</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1411</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>A bend charged with three stars.</Research_x0020_notes>
<Notes>&apos;§&apos; in the legend refers to a floral pattern.</Notes>
</Seal>
<Seal>
<Seal_x0020_owner>Zeno, Giovanni Battista</Seal_x0020_owner>
<Identifier>ZenoGB1</Identifier>
<Status>cardinal deacon</Status>
<Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>seal of dignity</Type_x0020_of_x0020_seal>
<Design>In an aedicule, the Virgin sitting, facing half-right, looking downwards, hands raised, held together; below, on the right, a figure facing left, looking upwards.</Design>
<Legend>S · BAPTISTE · ZENI · SANCTE [ . . . ] DIACON CARDINALIS VENETIS

[S. Baptiste Zeni Sancte [Marie in Porticu] (?). . . .  diaconi cardinalis Venetis]</Legend>
<Shape>pointed oval</Shape>
<Face>obverse</Face>
<Seal_x0020_titulus>Sta. Maria in Portico</Seal_x0020_titulus>
<Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>1468</Terminus_x0020_post_x0020_quem>
<Research_x0020_notes>Dans une niche à coquille d’architecture classique avec / avec entablement supporté par deux pilastres cannelés, la Vierge, nimbée, / de ¾ à droite, assise sur un siège sans dossier, les mains jointes / contemplant l’Enfant Jésus étendu sur ses genoux.  Au dessus de l’enta- / blement, sous une niche à coquille, le Père Eternel en buste, de face, / coiffé d’une tiare, bénissant, et tenant de la main gauche un globe. / De chaque coté pendent des guirlandes. / 
			Toute la partie inférieure du sceau est détruite</Research_x0020_notes>
</Seal>
</dataroot>
